黄金三镖客
小人
是贝克派你来的吗？
You're from Baker?
告诉他我把知道的都说出来了
Tell Baker that I told him all that I know already.
我现在只想安度余年 你懂吗？
Tell him I want to live in peace, understand?
这样折磨我一点用也没有
There is no use to go on tormenting me!
我对那笔钱的事一点都不知道
I know nothing at all about that case of coins.
若在钱失踪前他能听我的话
Now that gold has disappeared,but if he'd listened,
就不会有现在这种事发生
we could have avoided this altogether.
我到军事法庭去查过
I went to the army court.
根本没有人证
There were no witnesses.
所以他们什么也查不出来
They couldn't uncover any more.
钱的事我真的一无所知
I can't tell Baker what happened to the money.
请你照着我的话告诉他
Go back and tell him that.
听说有人来看过你
Word's around you had a visitor,
贝克也知道这件事
and Baker knows it.
他的名字叫杰克森
Name's Jackson.
是杰克森来过了
Well, Jackson was here
还是贝克搞错了
or Baker's got it all wrong.
他没搞错
He's not wrong.
也许贝克想知道
Maybe Baker would like to know
你们谈论的有关钱箱的事
just what you and Jackson had to say about the cash box.
不过他并没有付钱让我查钱箱的事
That's not what I'm being paid for.
所以我只想知道杰克森的化名
I'm only interested in what name Jackson's hiding under now.
为什么你认为杰克森有化名
Why do you think Jackson may be assuming another name?
否则我早就找到他了
I would have found him already.
我想找人 就一定能找到
When I start off to find somebody, I find him.
所以他们才愿意花钱雇我
That's why they pay me.
贝克付你多少？
What is Baker paying you?
那是你家人？
That's your family?
是的
Yes.
很幸福的家庭
Nice family.
他付你多少钱来杀我？
What does he pay you for murdering me?
五百美元
$500
来找出杰克森的化名
to get the name.
告诉我化名
The name.
是卡森 比尔·卡森
Carson. Bill Carson.
那就是他现在的名字
That's what he calls himself now.
这里有一千美元
That's a lot of money. $1,000.
一千美元？
$1,000?
居然还有黄金 数目真不小
And some in gold. That's a tidy sum.
可惜当我收了钱后 就一定会完成任务
But when I'm paid, I will see the job through.
是你
It's you.
有消息吗？
Any information?
他说了不少
Too much.
一些你感兴趣的
He said quite a bit that should interest you,
以及一些我感兴趣的
and one or two things that interested me.
比如？
Such as?
杰克森的化名是比尔·卡森
The name Jackson's hiding under is Bill Carson.
啊
Ah.
那是你想知道的
That's your bit.
继续讲
Keep talking.
他还提到钱箱之类的事
He also mentioned something about a certain cash box,
一个失踪的钱箱
which just happened to disappear.
这是我感兴趣的
That's my bit.
还有别的吗？
Anything else?
这还不够吗？
Not enough for you, eh?
你放心
Well, you don't have to worry.
他不会再讲话了
He'll never say anything to anybody again.
噢 干得好
Oh, yeah, yeah. Perfect.
给
Here you are.
这是付给你的钱
Here. This is for you.
你干得真不错
You did a good job for me.
的确值五百美元
Worth $500.
哎呀 我几乎忘了
Yeah. I almost forgot.
他付了我一千美元
He gave me $1,000.
想必是想让我杀了你
I think his idea was that I kill you.
问题是 只要我收了钱
But you know the pity is, when I'm paid,
就一定会完成任务
I always follow my job through.
这点你最清楚
You know that.
别！天使眼…
No! Angel Eyes...
坏人
朋友 别摸枪 对你没好处的
No. No pistol, amigo. It won't do you any good.
我们有三个人
There are three of us.
嘿 朋友
Hey, amigo.
你知道你这张俊脸至少值两千美元吗？
You know you've got a face beautiful enough to be worth $2,000?
没错
Yeah.
但你却不像是能领到赏金的人
But you don't look like the one who'll collect it.
向后退几步
A couple steps back.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你现在值多少？
How much are you worth now?
多少？
How much?
当然是两千美元
$2,000.
没错 是两千美元
That's right, $2,000.
对 两千块
Yeah, $2,000.
你个狗杂种
¡Hijo de una puta que te parió!
你会付出代价的
You'll pay for this! I hope you end up in a graveyard
祝你染上霍乱、狂犬病和瘟疫 最后痛苦地死掉
with the cholera and the rabies and the plague!
放开我
Cut me loose!
放开我 你这个混蛋
Cut me loose, you filthy bastard!
让我下来
Put me down!
愿你老妈沦为廉价妓女
I hope your mother ends up in a two-dollar whorehouse!
放开我
Cut me loose! Cut me loose!
你仍能拯救自己的灵魂
You can still save yourself.
放了我 我会原谅你的
Let me go, and I'll pardon you.
让我走
Let me go.
我不舒服
I think I feel sick.
血液上涌
The blood is bursting through my...
金发仔 我口渴
I'm dry, Blondie.
给我水
Water.
你这只猪 你个杂种 放我走！
You swine. You son of a bitch. Let me go!
欺负双手被绑的人 能叫英雄吗？
You're brave with a man who's tied up!
回来！
Come back!
我们公平地打一场
Come back and fight! You bastard.
怎么搞的
Who the hell is that?
一个混蛋进去 另一个混蛋出来
One bastard goes in, another comes out.
闭嘴！
Cut it out! Cut it out!
我是个诚实的农夫 我是被冤枉的…
I'm an honest farmer! I'm innocent of any...
那么 诚实的农夫 你认识这个人吗？
So, you're an honest farmer. You recognize this man?
我？
Me?
就是你
Yeah, it's you.
谁说是我 你连字都不认识
Me? Who says so? You can't even read.
卷起来 快卷起来
Yeah, roll it up. Roll it up.
把它挂哪儿我有个好建议
I'll give you a good idea where you can put it.
你们这些警长副警长 还有生养你们的人 全下地狱去吧
To hell with all you sheriffs and deputies and all who gave birth to you.
大家看呐 他居然给那家伙脏钱
Hey, everybody, look, look. He's giving him the filthy money.
犹大 你出卖我！
Judas. You sold my hide.
但你享受不到这些脏钱
But you won't enjoy any of that money, not a penny.
世上若有公理的话
If there's justice in the world,
这些钱都会成为你的棺材本儿
that money will go to the undertakers.
每个子儿都是
Every penny of it.
你知道你是谁吗？
You know who you are?
你知道你是谁的儿子吗？
You want to know whose son you are?
你当然知道 大家都知道
You don't, I do. Everybody does.
你有成千个老爸 而且和你一样 都是杂种
You're the son of a thousand fathers, all bastards like you.
还有你老妈…你老妈
And your mother... Your mother!
她是…你这个混蛋
She's... You bastard!
你老妈…都羞于提她
Your mother... It's better not to talk of her!
我从没伤过人
I never hurt anybody!
被本州十四个郡通缉
"Wanted in 14 counties of this state",
此犯犯有谋杀罪
"the condemned is found guilty of the crimes of murder,"
持枪抢劫市民、银行和邮局
"armed robbery of citizens,state banks and post offices,"
偷窃教会奉献金 在州立监狱纵火
"the theft of sacred objects,arson in a state prison,"
做伪证、重婚、抛弃发妻和孩子们
"perjury, bigamy, deserting his wife and children,"
逼女为娼、绑架、敲诈
"inciting prostitution, kidnapping, extortion,"
收赃货、卖赃货
"receiving stolen goods, selling stolen goods,"
使用伪钞 并且违反本州法律
"passing counterfeit money, and contrary to the laws of this state,"
使用做记号的纸牌和灌铅的骰子赌博
"the condemned is guilty of using marked cards and loaded dice."
依据法律
Therefore, according to the powers vested in us,
我们宣判被告
we sentence the accused here before us
图科班尼帝多派西非可黄玛利亚拉美尼斯
Tuco Benedicto Pacifico Juan Maria Ramirez...
名号“鼠仔”
Known as "The Rat."
或有其他别名
and any other aliases he might have
绞刑不同于吊刑
绞刑受刑部位是脖子
吊刑受刑部位是手腕
绞刑分为“吊死”和“勒死”两种
处以绞刑
to hang by the neck until dead.
愿上帝怜悯他的灵魂
May God have mercy on his soul.
行刑
Proceed.
五百给你 一、二…
Five for you. One, two
三、四、五 五百给我
three, four, five for me.
五百给你 五百给我
Five for you and five for me.
知道你现在值多少吗？
Know how much you're worth now?
不知道 多少？
No. How much?
三千美元
$3,000.
世界上有两种人
There are two kinds of people in the world, my friend,
一种是被绞的人
those with a rope around their neck,
一种是打断绞索的人
and the people who have the job of doing the cutting.
听着 我是被绞的人
Listen, the neck at the end of the rope is mine.
是拿老命去冒险的人
I run the risks.
所以下一次我要多分一点
So the next time,I want more than half.
你或许是在冒险 但我可是射断绳索的人
You may run the risks, my friend, but I do the cutting.
如果少分给我的话
If we cut down my percentage...
要雪茄吗？
Cigar?
我的瞄准就不会那么准
It's liable to interfere with my aim.
那就干脆瞄得非常不准
But if you miss, you had better miss very well.
如果谁害了我 却没把我害死
Whoever double crosses me and leaves me alive,
那他真是不了解图科
he understands nothing about Tuco.
毫不了解
Nothing.
被本州十五个郡通缉
"Wanted in 15 counties of this state."
站在我们面前的罪犯
"The condemned standing before us,"
应该说是坐在我们面前的罪犯
sitting before us,
图科班尼帝多派西非可黄玛利亚拉美尼斯
"Tuco Benedicto Pacifico Juan Maria Ramirez, has been found guilty"
被第三区巡回审判法庭判有以下罪状
"by the Third District Circuit Court of the following crimes,"
谋杀、攻击治安法官
"murder, assaulting a justice of the peace,"
强奸白种处女
"raping a virgin of the white race,"
强奸未成年黑人女孩
"statutory rape of a minor of the black race,"
使火车出轨以便抢劫乘客
"derailing a train in order to rob the passengers..."
嘿 天使眼
Hey, Angel Eyes.
抢劫银行、抢劫公路
"...bank robbery, highway robbery,"
抢劫邮局无数次 破坏…
"robbing an unknown number of post offices, breaking out..."
你有什么发现？
What'd you find out, Shorty?
你可是问对人了
If you ask me,it seems like a book.
一支军队护送一箱金币 遇到北军的埋伏
An armed unit escorting a cash box of gold coins
只有三个人活了下来
meets a Yankee ambush, and only three of them are saved.
史帝芬、贝克和杰克森
Stevens, Baker and Jackson.
可惜钱丢了
The thing that wasn't saved, though, was the coins.
后来军方听取杰克森的报告后
But then the army decides, of course,
将他无罪释放了
it ought to hold a hearing,and Jackson's acquitted.
他隐遁后化名比尔·卡森
He disappears and becomes Bill Carson.
我知道他的化名
I know his name.
但你不知道怎么去找他 只有我知道
But you don't know just who you're looking for, and I do.
他被找到的话肯定很惨
And when he's found, I'd be scared to be put in his shoes.
卡森在哪儿
Where's Carson?
我只知道他又参军了
All I know is Carson reenlisted.
那可怜的家伙瞎了一只眼
The poor guy's minus an eye.
他和玛丽亚住在一起 她会告诉你的
He lives with a girl called Maria who'll tell you.
她是新来的妓女
She's a fresh young whore in the territory.
她在哪儿？
Where's she?
某个镇
Now, what's the name of that town?
很近…
Someplace fairly near.
是圣塔安那
Santa Ana.
再见 半截士兵
Adios, half-soldier.
收容和贩卖潜逃奴隶 并焚毁…
...containing and selling absconding slaves, and burning down...
嘿 卢克 给我一杯威士忌
Hey, Luke, hand me down a whiskey.
…以及在索诺拉的警长办公室
"And the sheriff's office in Sonora."
罪犯曾充当蓬车队的向导
"The condemned hired himself out as a guide to a wagon train."
收到报酬后 却逃之夭夭
"After receiving his payment in advance, he deserted the wagon train"
把蓬车队留在苏族印地安人的狩猎区
"on the hunting grounds of the Sioux Indians."
好在他们抓到这个恶棍
Glad they got him, a man guilty of all those crimes.
有些人虽然被绞但不会死
People with ropes around their necks don't always hang.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
“谴责他人也有罪…”
"The condemned is also guilty..."
就算是那种肮脏的人 也有守护天使
Even a filthy beggar like that has got a protecting angel.
并冒充墨西哥将军
"...as a Mexican general."
有一个金发天使在照顾他
A golden-haired angel watches over him.
以上罪状
"For all these crimes,"
被告已主动承认
"the accused has made a full, spontaneous confession."
因此我们判决 处以绞刑
"Therefore, we condemn him to be hung by the neck until dead."
求上帝怜悯他的灵魂
May the Lord have mercy on his soul.
行刑！
Proceed.
咱们快离开这里
Let's get the hell out of here!
你想说任何人都有失手的时候吗？
What are you trying to say, anybody can miss a shot?
但绞着我脖子的时候 谁都不准失手
Nobody misses when I'm at the end of the rope.
你没有被绞的经验
You've never had a rope around your neck.
让我告诉你
Well, I'm going to tell you something.
绞索收紧的那一刻
When that rope starts to pull tight,
真有到了鬼门关的感觉
you can feel the devil bite your ass.
你说得不错 是越来越难了
Yeah, you're right. It's getting tougher.
我想你这小矮子
The way I figure, there's really not too much future
也没什么前途
with a sawed-off runt like you.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我认为你的身价不会超过三千美元
'Cause I don't think you'll ever be worth more than $3,000.
你到底想说什么？
What do you mean?
我说咱们的合伙关系到此为止
I mean, our partnership is untied.
对不起 你的手仍要绑住
Oh, no. Not you. You remain tied.
钱我留着 绳子就留给你吧
I'll keep the money, and you can have the rope.
你这个下流无耻的混蛋
You filthy, double-crossing bastard!
又脏又臭…
Of all the stinking, dirty tricks...
回城是七十英里
The way back to town is only 70 miles.
如果省着点力气
You know, if you save your breath,
相信你一定能办得到
I feel a man like you could manage it.
再见
你这个王八蛋 回来！
You filthy bastard! Come here!
回来 把绳索剪掉
Come here! Cut this rope off! Get off that horse.
下马 无耻的家伙
Get off that horse, you filthy coward!
如果让我再碰到你 一定把你的心挖出来吃掉
If I ever catch you, Blondie, I'll rip your heart out and eat it!
活剥头皮 活剥全皮
I'll scalp you! I'll skin you alive!
拇指吊刑
普通吊刑，行刑者先将犯人的手腕用绳子捆住
吊到一定高度再使其下落，在下落的冲力下
犯人的双臂会被拉得脱臼，犯人可能会因此死亡
吊刑还有一些更残忍的方式
其中一种是用细绳或铁丝将犯人的双手拇指捆扎并吊起
身体的重量全部落在两个大拇指上
处以拇指吊刑
I'll hang you up by your thumbs!
你这个蠢猪、贪心鬼！
You pig! You vulture!
我要杀了你！
I'll kill you! I'll kill you!
都救过你那么多次了 居然还这么忘恩负义
Such ingratitude, after all the times I've saved your life.
好人
你去哪？等等 你只是开玩笑
Where are you going? Wait a minute. This is only a trick.
你不会把我留在这里的
You wouldn't leave me here.
回来 等等 金发仔
Come back! Wait! Blondie!
听我说…
Listen, Blondie...
你这个杂种 听我说…
你这个杂种
¡Hijo de una gran puta!
相信女士的家到了
I believe madam is home.
祝你好梦 第七骑兵队谢谢你的服务
Sweet dreams, and many thanks from the Seventh Cavalry!
你们这些无耻之徒
You filthy rats!
玛丽亚
Maria.
- 甜心？ - 比尔 是你吗？
- Honey? - Is that you, Bill?
比尔！
Bill.
你是谁？你想干什么
Who are you? What do you want with me?
和你谈谈比尔·卡森的事
Go on talking about Bill Carson.
我不认识他
I don't know him.
你在黑暗中还叫着他的名字
You were calling to him in the dark.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
你想对他怎样？
What are you going to do to him?
是我在问你问题
I'll ask the questions.
他在哪儿？
Where is he?
他到底藏在哪里？
Where is he? Where?
在哪儿？
Where? Where? Where?
够了！
That's enough!
我不知道他在哪里
I don't know where he is.
十天前他就卷上他的东西
He packed his things ten days ago
跟他的部队一起走了 都走了
and went away with his unit. They all left.
是哪个连？到哪里去？
Which company? Where'd they go?
嗯？
Hmm?
席伯利将军属下的第三骑兵队
Third Cavalry, General Sibley.
他们去圣塔菲
They left for Santa Fe.
我发誓我只知道这么多
That's all I know, I swear!
但是…
But, but...
对不起 我已经打烊了
I'm very sorry, but the store's closing.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
左轮手枪
Revolvers.
对 左轮手枪
Yeah, revolvers.
给我看左轮手枪
Revolvers.
这里的都是最好的
Well, here's where I keep the best ones.
什么牌子都有 林明敦、科尔特
Here. Remington, Colt,
鲁特、史密斯威森、柯尔特、奈威
a Roat, Smith-Wesson, Colt, Navy,
约瑟林、另一种林明敦
Joslyn, another Remington.
够了
That's enough.
给我子弹
Cartridges.
要试枪的话 后面有靶子
You want to try the pistol?
我们走
- Just step out back. - Let's go.
快走
Move. Move.
子弹
Cartridge.
多少钱？
How much?
二十美元
$20.
不对吧
No.
五十块
$50.
多少？
How much?
一百块
$100
两百块 我只有这么多
$200. It's all I've got.
都在这里
Here.
你过来
Come here.
嗯？
Eh?
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
今早我听出个所以然来了
This morning, I heard the whole thing.
据他们说 北军的坎比上校正在途中
They say Colonel Canby's closing in with his Northerners,
最迟明天就会到这里
and no later than tomorrow that they'll be in the city.
所以南军才会走
That's why these Southerners are getting out.
你看一听到北军 南军就落荒而逃
You see, as soon as these cowards hear a Blue Shirt's around, they run.
这些叛军根本不想打仗
These Rebels have no will to fight.
真可怜
Poor things.
他们迟早会被消灭
They'll soon be finished.
把这些穷鬼送走 马上就可以在北佬身上发财了
We get rid of these bastards, then we begin making money on those Yankees.
他们身上只带金子
They carry gold, not paper dollars,
一定能打败南军
and they're going to beat the South.
你看坐在蓬车中白胡子的那位
Look. See that one with the white beard sitting in the wagon?
他是席伯利将军 看起来要死的样子
General Sibley. He looks dead.
他终于滚了
He's finally getting out of our hair.
南军加油！南军加油！
Hurray for Dixie! Hurray! Hurray for Dixie!
那匹马的主人在哪里？
Where's the owner of that horse?
先生 我心脏有毛病
Please, mister, sir, a bad heart condition...
他在哪儿？
Where?
战争已经快把我吓死了
The war has frightened me already.
我在找那匹马的主人
I'm looking for the owner of that horse.
他高大 金发 抽雪茄
He's tall, blond, he smokes a cigar,
还是只蠢猪 他在哪儿？
and he's a pig. Where is he now?
放开他 他都不知道哪个人骑哪匹马
You leave him be. He doesn't know who rides every horse.
老母鸡 你少管闲事
You stay quiet, old hen.
楼上 二楼四号房
Upstairs. Upstairs in room four, seńor.
听到了吧
Hear that?
你们这些坏掉渣的罪犯 真是胆大包天
You rotten criminals. How dare you?
要怪得怪你的马刺
Your spurs.
老友 有两种马刺
There are two kinds of spurs, my friend,
一种从房门进来
those that come in by the door,
另一种从窗户进来
those that come in by the window.
把枪带取下来
Take off that pistol belt.
那是空枪
It's empty.
我的枪可是满满的
Mine isn't.
犹大要上吊时 连老天都会打雷
Even when Judas hanged himself, there was a storm, too.
那好像是大炮
That could be cannon fire.
大炮和雷对你来说都一样
Cannon fire or storm, it's all the same to you.
你应该见过它吧
You ever see this before, my friend?
把它穿过横梁
Throw it over the roof beam.
就是那条
That's it.
你上去
Now get on that.
就是这样
That's right.
把绳索绑紧
Now make sure the rope is tight.
让它能吊住一只蠢猪
It's got to hold the weight of a pig.
把绳索套在你脖子上
Now put the rope around your neck.
很好
That's very good.
套索好像太大了
It's too big for your neck, huh?
我这就把它改到正好 当然是用另外的方法
We fix that right away. I have another system,
和你的有点不同
a little different than yours.
我不射绳子
I don't shoot the rope.
只射凳腿
I shoot the legs off the stool.
再见
Adios.
我们查到被告汤姆斯·来森 绰号矮子来森
"We have found the accused, Thomas Larson, alias Shorty Larson,"
犯有以下罪状
"guilty of the following crimes,"
偷马、偷窃北军的补给
"horse theft, theft of supplies belonging to the Union Army,"
偷窃南军的补给
"theft of supplies belonging to the Confederate Army,"
伤害两名自治会成员
"wounding two vigilantes,"
对贝瑞做人身攻击
"assault and battery on one named Barry O'Keefe,"
做伪证、敲诈、抢劫
"perjury, blackmail, robbery,"
越狱、扰乱治安
"escaping from a state prison,"
拉皮条、公路抢劫
"disturbing the peace, pandering, highway robbery..."
带上矮子？
And Shorty?
伪造和谋杀
"...forgery and murder."
所以根据本州既定法律
Therefore, with the powers vested in us by the laws of this state...
不
No.
不带？
No?
我们判汤姆斯·来森
We have condemned the aforementioned Thomas Larson,
绰号矮子来森 处以绞刑
alias Shorty Larson, to hang by the neck until dead.
愿上帝怜悯他的灵魂 行刑
May God have mercy on his soul. Proceed.
抱歉 矮子
Sorry, Shorty.
走 快点 我们走
Move. Come on, let's go.
真奇怪 每次一到沙漠 我就口渴
I don't know. As soon as I hit the desert, I'm thirsty.
皮肤灼伤了吗？据说浅色皮肤的人容易灼伤
Burns, huh? They say people with fair skin can't take too much.
我替你减点负重
Like that, you won't have to carry so much.
我们到哪去？
Where we going?
去我要去的地方
Where? Where I'm going, amigo.
在哪儿
Over that where.
一百英里之外 美丽而又干热的沙漠
Another 100 miles of beautiful, sunbaked sand.
就连军队也不敢走
Even the armies are afraid to march through there.
南方军队正在撤退
Sibley's men are retreating up there.
北方军队马上就要打过来
Canby's men are coming here.
但没人会到这个鬼地方来
But no one will set foot in this hell,
除了你和我
except you and me.
一百英里够你走的
100 miles, that's a nice walk.
上次你是怎么对我说的
What was it you told me the last time?
“如果省着点力气 相信你一定能办得到”
"If you save your breath, I feel a man like you could manage it."
如果办不到的话 老友 你就会死
And if you won't manage it, you'll die, only slowly,
而且会死得很慢 非常慢
very slowly, old friend.
你先请
After you, please. Start walking.
想休息吗？
Taking a rest?
金发仔 快点 没多远了
Come on, Blondie. We don't have very far to go.
只剩七十英里而已
Only 70 miles.
还有八个半钟头 太阳就要下山了
Only eight-and-a-half hours more before sunset.
不算太坏嘛
That's not too bad.
走呀
Come on.
金发仔 看来…
And so, Blondie,
咱们得说再见了
it's goodbye.
停 停下来
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Whoa, boy.
放松 没事了
Easy, easy. Easy, easy.
好马儿
Attaboy. That's nice.
南方联邦军队第三团
水 给我水
Water. Water.
只要给我水
$200,000 in gold.
二十万金币就是你的
It's yours. Just get me water.
你在说什么？
What's that you say?
你是谁？
Who the hell are you?
卡森
Carson.
我现在叫比尔·卡森
My name is Bill Carson now. It's Carson.
意外遇袭
Surprise attack.
全军覆灭 我的真名是杰克森 不是卡森
All dead. My name is Jackson, not Carson.
卡森 很高兴遇到你
Carson, Carson, yeah, yeah. Glad to meet you, Carson.
我是林肯的祖父 你刚刚说到钱是怎么回事
I'm Lincoln's grandfather. What was that you said about the dollars?
二十万全是我的
$200,000, all mine.
本来属于第三骑兵队的
Was the Third Cavalry's.
贝克一个子儿也没得到
Baker has nothing.
我把金币藏了起来 藏得很隐密
The gold, I hid the gold. The gold is safe.
在哪里？在这里吗？ 你说话呀 是不是这里
Where? Where, here? Here? Talk.
在公墓里
In the cemetery.
哪一个公墓
Which cemetery?
伤心坡的公墓
The one on Sad Hill.
墓名是…
There's a grave by...
是哪个坟墓？ 有名字吗？有号码吗？
Which grave? Have a name? Have a number?
快说 笨蛋 快说呀
Come on, you dummy, talk.
没有号码 只有名字
There's no number. There's a name.
名字是…
It's written...
是什么？
Yes?
水！
Water.
你先说 我等会儿给你水喝
You talk first, huh? I'll give you water later.
在伤心坡的一个坟墓里
Sad Hill Cemetery. Okay.
在坟墓里 好吧
In the grave. Okay.
但应该有名字或是号码吧
But it must have a name or a number on it, huh?
那里的坟有好几千座 至少也有五千个
There must be a thousand,five thousand.
水…
water...
别死啊
Don't die, huh?
你别死 我去拿水
Don't die. I'll get you water.
你待在这里别动 我去拿水
Stay there. Don't move. I'll get you water.
等告诉我名字后再死 你这该死的…
Don't die until later, you son of a...
你滚开
Get away from there.
他死了
He's dead.
是的
Yeah.
我会杀了你
I'll kill you.
杀了我 你会穷一辈子
If you do that, you'll always be poor,
就像现在一样
just like the greasy rat that you are.
若我是你 一定会千方百计地让我活下去
If I were you, I'd keep me alive.
他告诉你什么？
What did he tell you, huh?
一个名字
A name.
一个坟墓的名字
A name on a grave.
什么名字？
What name?
你别死呀
Blondie, don't die.
金发仔 你千万别死 我是你的朋友
Blondie, don't die. I'm your friend.
求求你别死
Please don't die. Please.
我是你的朋友啊 振作点
I'm your friend. Come on. Come on.
金发仔
Blondie.
我会帮你的 我会帮你的
I'll help you. I'll help you.
你别动 我马上就回来
Don't move. I'll be right back.
水来了 别成死猪呀
Here's the water. Don't die like that pig.
喂 金发仔 水来啦 水在这里
Hey, Blondie, here's water. Water, Blondie.
先别喝 这样对身体不好
Don't drink, don't drink. Is no good for you.
好点了吗？
Feel better?
金发仔 这是怎么搞的
Blondie, what's the matter?
你一定要活下去
Please, don't die.
我的同伴病得很重
I've got a very sick man here.
但我们已经没有床位了
But we have no more beds here.
那就把你的让出来吧
Let him have yours.
巴布罗·拉美尼斯在哪里？
Where's Pablo Ramirez?
是拉美尼斯神父
Father Ramirez.
他暂时离开了 随时都会回来
He's away at the moment. He should be back any day now.
没关系
Well, it doesn't matter.
我们先好好照顾这个朋友
For the moment, we take very good care of my friend.
感谢主
And may God be praised.
告诉你一件事 上帝是站在我们这边的
In case you didn't know it,God is on our side, too,
因为他不喜欢北方佬 对不对 金发仔？
because he hates the Yanks huh, Blondie?
金发仔？ 神父 他还在呼吸么？
Blondie? Father, is he still breathing?
当然
Yes, of course.
你可真重
You're heavy.
去里面
There.
给他换个新的绷带
All right, put a fresh bandage on him.
把他放在我的房间里
Put him in my cell.
小心点
Easy.
士兵 你出去 快点
Out, soldier. Out you go. Come on.
好好照顾他 他和我情同手足
Look out for him, please. He's like a brother to me.
神父 我…
Hey, Father, I...
神父 他说话了吗？ 他说什么了吗？
Father, did he speak? Did he say anything?
神父 他有没有问起我？ 有没有说任何事？
Father, did he ask for me? Did he speak about anything, Father?
他还不能说话
Oh, no, he hasn't spoken as yet.
不过你不要担心
But you mustn't worry.
他年轻又强壮
He's both young and strong.
所以才能撑到现在
That's what's kept him going until now.
要不了多久他就能活蹦乱跳了
He should regain his strength in a very short time.
谢谢你 神父 谢谢你
Thank you, Father. Thank you.
他对我实在太重要了
You don't know how much this boy's life means to me.
感谢耶稣 感谢你们
Thanks be to Jesus. Thanks to all of you.
金发仔
Blondie.
嘿 金发仔
Hey, Blondie.
神父告诉我 过几天你就会好了
The old father tells me you'll be up and around in a few days.
幸好当时我在你身边
You're very lucky to have me so close when it happened.
如果只有你一个人
Think if you'd been on your own.
我是说 当…
Look, I mean, when...
当一个人生病时
When one is ill,
最好能有人在身边 不管是朋友还是亲戚
it's good to have somebody close by, friends or relations.
你父母还在吗？妈妈呢？
Do you have parents, Blondie? A mother?
妈妈也不在了
Not even a mother.
一个亲戚也没有吗？
No one?
只有你一个人吗？ 像我一样
You're all alone, huh? Like me, Blondie.
我们都在世上独自漂泊
We're all alone in the world.
我只有你 你也只有我
I have you, you have me.
这当然只是暂时的
Only for a little while, I mean.
但却碰巧发生了
It had to happen now.
都是命运在做怪
What a dirty, rotten trick of fate.
那些钱几乎到了我们手中
We could have all that money in our hands.
我必须告诉你真相
I must tell you the truth, Blondie.
换成你也会做同样的事
In my place, you would do the same thing.
你已经没有希望了
It's all over for you now.
没人救得了你
There's nothing anyone can do anymore.
天啊 这都是我的错
God help me. It's my fault.
是我的错呀
Mine, mine, mine, mine.
告诉你一件事
I'll tell you one thing, Blondie.
如果我知道只有一小时好活
If I knew that my last hour had come, I swear
若咱们换个位置 我发誓一定会做同样的事
in my place, in your place,I would do the same thing.
就是告诉你金币在哪里 是的 是的 我会告诉你
I would tell about the gold. Yes. Yes, I would.
告诉你坟墓的名字
I'd tell the name on the grave.
你是将死之人 钱生不带来死不带去
After all, what good is the money to you if you're dead?
我知道公墓在哪
I know the name of the cemetery,
但那儿有成千的坟墓
but you know how many graves there are there?
求求你告诉我吧
Please, Blondie.
来 喝点咖啡吧
Please, have a little, huh? Here. Coffee.
求求你告诉我
Please, tell me the name
坟墓上的名字
on the grave.
如果我拿到二十万的话
If I get my hands on the $200,000,
保证永远不会忘记你
I'll always honor your memory.
我发誓永远记得你
I swear, I'll always honor your memory.
靠近点
Come closer.
快告诉我
Tell me.
你这个卑鄙的…
Well, you dirty...
知道身边有个好朋友
I'll sleep better
随时都在保护我
knowing my good friend is by my side
连睡觉都能睡得安稳些
to protect me.
-“图科 给我水” -水来啦
-"Tuco, water." -Well, here's water.
如果让我知道名字的话 看我会给你什么样的水
But if I get that name from you, I'll give you water.
好了 懒鬼 起床吧
All right, you dirty skunk, get your ass off the bed.
快起来 我们得走了
Come on, come on, the party's over.
蓬车已经准备好了
The wagon is all ready to go.
受伤的人越来越多
From the way the wounded are pouring into this place,
我们最好快走
we better get the hell out of here
战争就要来了
before we get caught up in the war.
图科 拉美尼斯神父回来了
Tuco, Father Ramirez is back.
好的
Yeah.
我得去办点事
This is something I have to look into.
只要几分钟 你先准备一下
It'll only take a minute. Get moving.
- 这边？ - 是的
- Where, this way? - Yes.
巴布罗
Hey, Pablo.
你认不得我了吗？
Don't you recognize me?
我是图科 让我抱抱你
It's me, Tuco. Let me embrace you.
我不知道这样做是不对的
I don't know the right thing.
经过这里时 我在想
I was just passing by here, I said to myself,
“不知道我哥哥 还记不记得我这个弟弟”
"I wonder if my brother remembers his brother."
我做错了吗？
Did I do wrong?
没关系 看到你我真高兴
It doesn't matter. I'm very happy.
你见到我了 图科
You have seen me, Tuco.
对呀 真高兴我能来
Yeah, well, I'm very glad I came.
喔 我这身制服吗？ 说来话长
Oh, my uniform. It's a long story.
让我们先谈谈你 你比较重要
But let's talk about you. It's more important.
你看起来很不错
You look very well.
也许瘦了一点 但是…
A bit thin, perhaps, but...
你本来就很瘦嘛 对吧？
you were always thin, eh, Pablito?
爸妈好吗？
What about our parents?
你现在才想到他们
Only now do you think of them.
九年之后才开始想起
To begin after nine years.
已经有九年了吗？
Nine years?
九年就九年吧
So it's nine years. Nine years.
母亲很久以前就死了
Our mother has been dead a long time now.
父亲在几天前才过世
Our father died only a few days ago.
所以我才会离开这里
That's why I was away.
他临死前想见见你
He asked for you to be there,
可惜只有我在那儿送终
but there was only me.
而你
And you?
你这个野鬼 你都做了些什么
Outside of evil, what else have you managed to do?
我记得你曾有过妻子
It seems to me you once had a wife someplace.
不只一个 有好多个
Not one, lots of them.
这里一个 那里一个 只要她们愿意 我就照单全收
One here, one there, wherever I found them.
说呀 向我说教呀
Go on, preach me a sermon, Pablo.
那有什么用
What good would that be?
你仍然照做不误
Just keep on the way you're going.
你走吧
Go away.
愿上帝怜悯你的灵魂
And the Lord have mercy on your soul.
好 我走 我走！
Sure, I'll go, I'll go.
等上帝记起我之前
While I'm waiting for the Lord to remember me,
请让我图科 巴布罗的弟弟
I, Tuco Ramirez, brother of Brother Ramirez,
说几句
will tell you something.
你一直觉得自己比我强
You think you're better than I am.
在我们土生土长的那个鬼地方 如果不想饿死
Where we came from, if one didn't want to die of poverty,
除了当神父 只能当土匪
one became a priest or a bandit.
你选择你的路 我也选择我的
You chose your way, I chose mine.
我的路比你的要艰难得多
Mine was harder!
说到爸妈
You talk about Mother and Father.
还记得当初你去当神父时 是我留守在家吗？
You remember, when you left to become a priest, I stayed behind.
我当时十岁出头吧 记不清了 但我留下来了
I must have been 10, 12. I don't remember which, but I stayed.
我曾努力拼过 但没用
I tried, but it was no good.
现在 让我告诉你
Now I will tell you something.
你之所以去做神父 是因为你懦弱 没我那个胆量
You became a priest because you were too much of a coward to do what I do.
图科
Tuco.
弟弟 原谅我吧
Please forgive me, brother.
哇 我肚子胀得要命
My belly's full.
我哥哥是个好人
Nice guy, my brother.
我没告诉你 我哥哥是这里的主持吧
I didn't tell you my brother was in charge here?
管着一切 几乎和教皇一样
Everything. Like the pope almost.
而教皇是罗马的主持 还有 我哥哥对我说
He's in charge in Rome. Yeah, yeah, my brother, he say to me,
“弟弟 不要走 留下来”
"Stay, brother. Don't go home."
“否则我们再也见不到了”
"We never see each other."
“这里有吃有喝 让你的朋友也留下来”
"Here there's plenty to eat and drink. Bring your friend, too."
每次我们见面 他都不让我走
Whenever we see each other, he never lets me go.
总是这样
It's always the same story.
我哥哥对我好得不得了
My brother, he is crazy about me.
你看像我这种流浪汉 不管发生了什么事
That's so. Even a tramp like me, no matter what happens,
只要到我哥哥那儿去 一日三餐绝对不用愁
I know there's a brother somewhere who will never refuse me a bowl of soup.
没错
Sure.
酒足饭饱后 来根雪茄吧
Well, after a meal, there's nothing like a good cigar.
哇
Whoa.
喂 你醒醒
Hey, wake up, you.
有军队过来了
The troops are coming. Come on.
蓝色还是灰色
Blue or gray?
和我们一样的灰色 咱们和他们打个招呼吧
They're gray like us. Let's say "hello" to them and then get going.
加油！南军加油
Hoorah! Hoorah for the Confederacy!
加油！格兰特将军加油
Hoorah! Down with General Grant!
- 加油…另外一个是什么将军 - 李将军
- Hoorah for General... What's his name? - Lee.
李将军加油
Lee! Lee!
上帝与我们同在 因为他也讨厌北军
God is with us because he hates the Yanks, too!
上帝去另一边了 因为他讨厌白痴
God's not on our side 'cause he hates idiots also.
踏步走、二、三、四
Hut, two, three, four. Hut, two, three, four.
向前走、二、三、四
Hut, two, three, four.
战俘们
Prisoners of war,
向前走
forward march!
立正
Halt!
向左转
Left face!
列成一排 快！
Form a single file. Move!
乔纳森·弗罗斯特
Jonathan Frost!
在
Present!
理查德·麦吉利
Richard McGilley!
在
Present!
纳撒尼尔·沙利文
Nathaniel Sullivan!
在
Present.
罗伯特·克拉克
Robert Clark!
在
Present.
山姆·里士满
Sam Richmond!
在
Present.
比尔·卡森！
Bill Carson!
我在叫比尔·卡森！
I said Bill Carson!
金发仔 那个人不就是天使眼吗？
Hey, Blondie, isn't that Angel Eyes?
他在干什么 打瞌睡吗？
All right, what's he doing, sleeping?
比尔·卡森！
Bill Carson!
没错 你最好装成比尔·卡森
Yeah, and you better be Bill Carson.
比尔·卡森
Bill Carson!
是我
Yeah, that's me.
卡森 当你回答时
Please, Carson,
要说“在”
answer "present."
你聋了吗？
What are you, deaf?
卡森 你该说“在”
Now suppose you say "present," Carson.
我喜欢你这种大胖子
I like big fat men like you.
跌倒时声音特别大 有时候跌倒了就起不来
When they fall, they make more noise, and sometimes they never get up.
华莱士
Wallace,
够了
that's enough.
中士！
Sergeant!
上尉马上要见你
The captain wants to see you right away.
好好对待这两位
Be sure these two get good treatment.
嘿 金发仔 你听到了吗？
Hey, Blondie, did you hear that?
好好对待我们
Good treatment.
听到了
Yeah.
我再警告你一次 中士
For the last time, Sergeant,
你要用正确的方法对待战俘
I'm telling you, I want the prisoners treated as prisoners.
不能使用暴力
No more brutality.
我们有好几百个战俘
There's hundreds of prisoners out there
但只有几个守卫
and only a few men to guard them.
你说我该怎么办？ 我必须要得到他们的敬重
Now what am I supposed to do? I have to have respect.
若对他们好一点
I think that you'll manage to gain their respect
更容易得到他们的敬重
by treating them better.
安德森维尔战俘营 对我们的人好吗？
Are our men treated that well in Andersonville camp?
我不管他们怎么做
I don't give a God damn what they do in Andersonville.
我负责这里 不希望看到战俘被拷打
While I'm in charge here, the prisoners are not to be tortured,
被欺骗或被谋杀
or cheated or murdered.
你在指控我吗？
That an accusation?
中士 我是腿坏了 不是眼瞎了
Sergeant, gangrene is eating my leg away, not my eyes.
我知道战俘们被有计划地抢劫
I know the prisoners here are being robbed systematically.
也知道那些渣滓们露宿战俘营外
I know there's scum around who are bivouacked near the camp
就等着里面的人送掠夺品出去
waiting for someone to deliver this loot.
但只要我当指挥官一天 就不准这种奸计得逞
But as long as I'm commandant, I won't permit any such trickery.
- 懂了么？ - 是的 长官
- Am I clear? - Yes.
只要你仍是指挥官
Just as long as you're the commandant.
很好 中士
Yes, Sergeant.
我知道我活不了多久
I know this leg means I won't last very long,
只求有足够的时间收集证据
but I pray I can manage to have enough time to amass evidence
把败坏军队声誉的那些人
and bring to a court-martial
送到军事法庭上去
all those who discredit and dishonor the uniform of the Union.
祝你好运
I wish you luck.
比尔·卡森
你们最近要收敛一点
You and the others better lay low for a few days.
这个留下 你走吧
No, I'll keep this. You go.
华莱士会通知你们的
Wallace will let you know.
把卡森带进来
Wallace, bring me Carson.
好
Right.
天使眼要我们最近收敛点
Listen, Angel Eyes said for us to lay low for a few days,
但要守在附近随时注意情况
but we'll keep close enough to keep an eye on things.
走 给马备鞍吧
Come on, saddle your horses.
进去
Get in.
图科 进来 不要害羞
Come on in, Tuco. Don't be bashful.
我这里不拘形式
There's no formalities here.
好久没见
It's been a long time.
你饿了吧 坐下来吃饭
You're hungry. Sit down, eat.
我就知道
I knew it, I knew it.
我一见到你就对自己说
The minute I saw you,I said to myself,
“天使眼那家伙”
"Look at that pig, Angel Eyes."
“肯定找了份轻松的差事”
"I'll bet he got himself an easy job,"
“而且绝不会忘记朋友”
"and he never forgets a friend."
我是不会忘记老朋友的
I never forget old friends, Tuco.
对
Right.
很高兴能见到你这个老朋友
It's good to see old friends again.
很好
Good.
尤其是来自远方的朋友
Especially when they've come from so far away
一定有很多话要说
and have so much to talk about.
相信你一定有很多话要说
And you do have a lot to talk about, haven't you?
你是在葛瑞堡被俘的
You were captured near Fort Craig.
若你跟着席伯利的军队走
Well, if you were with Sibley, that means then
那表示你是从圣塔菲过来的
that you were coming from Santa Fe.
穿过沙漠不是很困难吗？
Was it hard crossing the desert?
非常困难
Mmm-Hmm. Very hard.
尤其是没东西喝
Especially if you don't have anything to drink.
为什么你用比尔·卡森这个名字
Why are you going under the name of Bill Carson now?
什么名字还不都一样
One name is as good as another.
只要不用真名就行了
Not wise to use your own name.
像你
Like you.
也不会用天使眼吧
I'll bet they don't call you Angel Eyes.
天使眼中士
Sergeant Angel Eyes.
你在吃饭时喜欢听音乐吗？
Like a little music with your meal, Tuco?
音乐？当然好 非常有利消化
Music? Yes, it's very good, very good for the digestion.
这么说
So...
比尔·卡森是个假名啰
Bill Carson's a fake name, huh?
那这个也是假的吗？
That fake, too?
比尔·卡森的名字就写在上面
Bill Carson's name's written in it.
来一点 那是他的烟叶
Have some. It's Bill Carson's tobacco.
当你发现卡森时 他是死是活？
Was Carson dead or alive when you found him?
有关钱的事他都说了些什么？
What'd he tell you about the money?
我不…
I don't...
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
多加点感情进去
More feeling.
你的运气比你朋友要好得多
You can sure consider yourself much luckier than your pal.
只要音乐不停 华莱士就会一直揍你的朋友
Wallace will punch your friend as long as the song goes.
我们几乎都经历过那种拷打
So many of us have had a session in there.
消化得怎样了？
How's your digestion now?
你最好实话实说
You'd better talk.
我没什么好说的
I have nothing to tell you.
你！继续拉小提琴
Play that fiddle, you.
够了 我说 我说
Enough. Enough. I talk. I talk.
他是怎么说钱的事？
What did he say about the money?
埋…在坟墓里
It's buried in a grave.
在哪里？
Where?
伤心坡
Sad Hill.
伤心坡公墓
Sad Hill Cemetery.
哪一个坟墓
Which grave?
不知道 我是真的不知道
I don't know. I don't know, I tell you.
去问金发仔
Blondie. Ask Blondie.
他知道墓名
He knows the name on the grave.
对你来说战争已经结束
War's over for you.
把衣服穿上
Put those clothes on.
为什么？
Why?
我们出去走走
We're going for a ride.
去哪儿？
Where?
去找二十万美元
To find $200,000.
我知道公墓在哪里
I know the name of the cemetery now,
而你知道是哪个坟墓
and you know the name of the grave.
难道你不打算给我同样的待遇吗？
You're not gonna give me the same treatment?
你会招吗？
Would you talk?
可能不会
No, probably not.
如我所料
That's what I thought.
不是说你比图科勇敢
Not that you're any tougher than Tuco,
而是你知道说出来命也没了
but you're smart enough to know that talking won't save you.
那图科他…
And Tuco, is he...
还没死
No. Not yet.
不过有人会好好照顾他的
But he's in very good hands.
你的合伙人虽然不一样 但交易仍旧不变
You've changed partners, but you still got the same deal.
我并不贪心 只拿一半就好
I'm not greedy. I'm only taking a half.
两个人
There's two of us.
比一个人要好办事
It should make it easier than just one.
对
Yeah.
保持这个样子 很好 不要动
Hold it. That's it, don't move.
不要呼吸 不要动 就是这样
Now don't breathe. Still. That's it.
好了 谢谢你们
Got it. Thank you.
下士 你怕他会逃吗？
Hey, Corporal, afraid he'll get lost?
这个叛徒要押到哪里去
Where's the rebel going?
带着赏金和绞索去地狱
To hell, with a rope around his neck and a price on his head.
老兄 三千块呀
Yeah, $3,000, friend.
我的脑袋可值不少钱
That's a lot of money for a head.
我赌你这条断臂 他们连一毛也没付
I'll bet they didn't even pay you a penny for your arm.
我只说一遍 下次若被我揍倒在地
I told you once, friend, if I ever get you down,
你就别想再起来
you're gonna need a lot of help to get up again. A lot.
你比车头那家伙要幸运多了
You're a lot luckier than that one there.
几道手续 一根绳子 你就呜呼哀哉了
You get some trouble, rope, and you're all finished.
这次不会再有搭档来救你了
And there isn't any partner this time to shoot you down.
你真以为偷得到吗？
Sure would like to put your paw on it, huh?
我要小便 憋不住了
I would like to piss. It's rough.
在火车上已经颠簸了将近十个小时
I've been shaken up on this train nearly ten hours now.
你已经闻起来和猪一样
You smell like a pig already,
最好收敛点 别让自己更糟糕
but let's not try to make things any worse.
来
Get going.
你看着我就撒不出来
I can't while you're watching me.
一路你吵得要死
You made a lot of noise, my friend, huh?
既然你不想破坏我们的友情 那就让我来破坏好了
You don't want to break our friendship, huh? Well, I'll break it.
停下
Halt.
就位
Take your places.
准备！
Ready!
瞄准！开枪！
Aim! Fire!
瘦子 你来照顾马匹
Slim, take care of the horses.
我找你找了八个月
I've been looking for you for eight months.
每次我想用右手拿枪时
Whenever I should've had a gun in my right hand,
就会想到你
I thought of you.
老天帮忙 居然让我在澡盆里找到你
Now I find you in exactly the position that suits me.
我花了很多时间 练习用左手开枪
I had lots of time to learn how to shoot with my left.
要开枪就开枪 何必废话那么多
When you have to shoot,shoot. Don't talk.
每支枪都有它自己的声音
Every gun makes its own tune.
你真会选时间
It's perfect timing, Large One.
克莱蒙 你去跟着他
Clem, follow him.
等一下 我马上就来
Just a minute. I'll be right there.
给我一点时间穿衣服 马上就来开门
Just give me a little time to get dressed, and I'll open up.
把枪放下 把衣服穿上
Put your drawers on and take your gun off.
嗨 金发仔 你是怎么逃离那个猪舍的
Hey, Blondie, how the hell did you get out of that pigsty?
我自有方法 我和你的老朋友一起来的 天使眼
My own way. I'm here with your old friend, Angel Eyes.
你招了 你居然告诉他了
You talked, you traitor. You talked.
我没说
No, I didn't talk.
倘若说出来 我早就死了
If I did, I probably wouldn't be here now.
你…我…
You, me...
所以只有你知道那半个秘密吗？
So only you know your half of the secret?
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
金发仔
Blondie,
真高兴你和我站在一条阵线上 再度合作
I'm very happy you're working with me, and we're together again.
我把衣服穿上 杀了他后 马上回来
I get dressed, I kill him and be right back.
喔 对了 我忘了说一件事
Oh, listen, I forgot to mention,
他不是一个人 是五个人
he's not alone. There's five of them.
五个人？
Five?
是的 一共五个人
Yeah, five of them.
所以你才来找我？
So that's why you came to Tuco?
没关系 反正我会把他们全部杀光
It doesn't matter. I'll kill them all.
他被近距离打死的
They shot him at close range.
哦 看是谁来了
Well, look who's here.
另一个随后也会跟来
The other one will be along.
他们是来找我们的
They'll come looking for us.
大家小心
Watch out.
他们一共有两个人
There's two of them.
我要活捉金发仔
I want that blond alive.
你们走那边 动身吧
You, back there. Come on, let's go.
你想一个人去送死吗？
Were you gonna die alone?
别动！
Halt!
喂 金发仔 天使眼是我的
Hey, Blondie, Angel Eyes is mine, huh?
没问题
All right.
“稍后见 白…白…”
"See you soon, I... Idi..."
“白痴”
"Idiots."
给你的
It's for you.
这里既平静又美丽
How peaceful and quiet, amigo.
就像墓地一样 是吗？
Like a cemetery, for instance?
应该有座桥横跨那条河
There should be a bridge across that river.
最好等晚上再行动
We'd better wait for nightfall.
相信我
Trust in me, Blondie.
我对目的地有一种很好的预感
I got a good sense of where I'm going.
既然能把你带到这里来
Tuco has taken you this far.
就能把你带到目的地
I will take you all the way...
先生们
Gentlemen.
- 去告诉上尉 - 是的 长官
- Tell the captain. - Yes, sir.
跟我走
Come along now. Follow me.
我们在阵地附近发现他们
We found them near the perimeter, sir.
你们来自何处？
Where do you hail from?
伊利诺州
Illinois.
你呢？
And you?
我和他一道
I'm with him.
因何来此？
Any reason for being around here?
将军 我们想从军
We want to enlist, General.
你最好学会认军阶
You better learn to distinguish rank.
我是上尉
I'm a captain.
你们可以走了
Get the hell out.
也许今天性命就不保 去写遗嘱吧
It sure as hell might be you today, so go write your will.
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
你们想从军
So you want to enlist?
首先得看你们合不合格
You gotta take a test to prove it.
你敢喝吗？
Well, show me.
你没问题
You've got a career.
至少能做到上校
At the least, I'd say you'll make colonel.
- 真的吗？ - 当然
- Really? - Sure.
就像手册中所说的
Like it says in the manual, "You've got every qualification,"
“你已成为使用武器的专家”
"to become an expert in the use of weapons."
这玩意就是最有力的武器
For this, sir, is the most potent weapon in war.
瓶子里的就是战斗的精神
The fighting spirit's in this bottle.
自愿者
Volunteers.
你们想从军是吗？
You want to enlist?
咱们走
Let's go. Come on, gentlemen. Come on.
攻击还没开始
The shooting hasn't begun yet.
你们正好赶上战斗
Yes, because soon you can join
可以做布兰森大桥战役中的英雄
the gallant heroes of Branson Bridge.
我们在一天中进攻了两次
We have two attacks a day.
一天攻了两次？
Two attacks a day?
南方认为
Sure, the Rebs have decided that damn bridge
这座桥是占领这个地区的关键
is the key to this whole area.
这座又乏味又没用的桥
Stupid, useless bridge.
不过是总部地图上的一个小点
Flyspeck on headquarters' maps.
但总部却下令一定要占领这座桥
And headquarters has declared we must take that ridiculous flyspeck
即使全军覆没也在所不惜
even if all of us are killed.
否则先机尽失
Otherwise, the key will get rusty and just be a spot on the wall.
而且
And that's not all.
双方都不希望桥梁受损
Both sides want the bridge intact.
南方希望它完好无损 我们也是
Intact is how the South wants it, and we want it intact, too.
你们全将化为尘土
You'll all turn to dust,
但有件事我绝对肯定 就是布兰森大桥将永存
but one thing is sure, boys, Branson Bridge will stand unbroken.
我这样对志愿者讲话 会不会吓坏你们？
Is it bad to speak the way I do to volunteers?
我以前更吓人
I've done a lot worse.
“我把它炸掉了 把它全毁了 嘭——”
I've done it. I've blown it up. Boom.
可惜只能想想
In here, I've destroyed it all.
你知道炸掉它的罪有多大吗
It's a court-martial offense to imagine,
将来一定会面临军事法庭的审判
to dream of blowing it up. A serious crime.
即使在脑袋里想想也会…
Even to think of destroying that bridge is just...
为什么不真地去炸掉它
Why not really blow it up, Captain?
对呀 又简单 又会吓得他们屁滚尿流
Yeah, Captain, it's nothing. Let's scare the hell out of them.
说实话 我连做梦都想
I've been dreaming about it.
甚至还想出个计划来
I've even worked out a plan.
真的
I sure have.
最好的时机是在攻击过后
The best time is after the attack
去救受伤者而暂时休战的时刻
when there's a truce to get the wounded.
如果那时去炸桥 就会救了上千人的性命
If I could do it, I could save many thousands of men.
可是我缺乏胆量
But what I lack is the guts.
他们开始攻击了
They're beginning their daily slaughter right on time.
上尉 所有的连都准备好了 就等你的命令
Captain, all companies are awaiting your orders.
马上就来
Be right there.
咱们走吧
Let's go.
好啦 朋友们 一起来享受这个壮观场面吧
All right, friends, come along and enjoy the spectacle.
各连报告
Companies, report!
B连准备好了
Company B ready!
E连准备好了
Company E ready!
D连准备好了
Company D ready!
各连进攻！
Companies, forward!
嘿 金发仔
Hey, Blondie,
看来上尉好像要我们帮他去炸桥
it looks like the captain is really asking for a bullet in his guts.
对
Yeah.
我从没见过这么多人无意义的死去
I've never seen so many men wasted so badly.
看来这场战役会很漫长
I have a feeling it's really gonna be a good, long battle.
- 金发仔 - 嗯？
- Blondie? - Huh?
钱是在河的那一边
The money's on the other side of the river.
在哪里？
Where?
告诉你在对岸已经够多了
Amigo, I said the other side, and that's enough.
若南军守在那里 我们就过不去
But while the Confederates are there, we can't get across.
如果桥被炸掉的话 会怎样呢？
What would happen if somebody were to blow up that bridge?
没错
Yeah.
那他们就得到别的地方去打仗
Then these idiots would go somewhere else to fight.
也许吧
Maybe.
炸药
医生 快来 上尉受伤了
Doctor, quick, the captain's wounded.
快拿担架来
Hurry, a stretcher.
慢点
Easy. Easy now.
快把东西准备好
Get things ready.
喝点酒会有帮助的
A little of this will help.
先来一口
Take a slug of this, Captain.
然后留心听着
Keep your ears open.
你们想干嘛？别伤害我
What are you doing? No... Leave me alone...
你知道我们有丧命的可能吗？
Blondie, you realize we might be risking our lives.
当然知道 但是万一我死了
Yeah, and if I get killed,
你就永远找不到金币
you'll never get your hands on all that beautiful money.
图科 你想想看
Yeah, Tuco,
是不是太可惜了
it sure would be a pity.
医生
Doc.
Doctor,
请让我撑久一点好吗？
could you help me live a little more?
我正在等个好消息
I expect good news.
我们干脆把知道的告诉对方好不好？
Why don't we tell each other our half of the secret?
好主意
Why don't we?
你先说
You go first.
不 我认为你先说
No, I think it's better that
比较好
you start.
好啦
All right.
公墓的名字是…
The name of the cemetery is...
伤心坡 现在该你了
Sad Hill. Now it's your turn.
坟墓上的名字是…
The name on the grave is
奥奇·史坦顿
Arch Stanton.
奥奇·史坦顿？ 你确定？
Arch Stanton? Are you sure?
我当然确定
Yeah, sure, I'm sure.
奥奇·史坦顿之墓
卒于1862年2月3日
用那个挖容易得多
It'll be a lot easier with that.
两个人挖比一个人挖要快得多
Two can dig a lot quicker than one.
快挖
Dig.
你怎么不挖
You're not digging.
如果杀了我 你一个子儿也见不到
If you shoot me, you won't see a cent of that money.
为什么？
Why?
我告诉你为什么
I'll tell you why.
因为钱不在那里
'Cause there's nothing in there.
你这个狗杂…
Why, you son of a...
你以为我真会相信你？
You thought I'd trust you?
别忘了二十万是笔大数目
$200,000 is a lot of money.
我们必须去赢得它
We're gonna have to earn it.
怎么赢得？
How?
我把名字写在这个石头下面
I'll write the name on the bottom of this stone.
然后比枪
The gun.
你这只猪 居然陷害我 你什么时候把子弹取出来的
You pig. You want to get me killed? When'd you unload it?
昨晚
Last night.
这个世界上有两种人
You see, in this world, there's two kinds of people, my friend,
一种人的枪装满子弹 一种人只会挖坟
those with loaded guns, and those who dig.
你去挖坟吧
You dig.
挖哪里？
Where?
这里
Here.
无名者之墓
可是这个没有名字
There's no name on it!
石头上也没名字
There's no name here either.
当初比尔·卡森告诉我
You see, that's what Bill Carson told me.
钱是在奥奇·史坦顿之墓旁边的无名冢里
It was the grave marked "Unknown" right beside Arch Stanton.
挖吧
Go ahead.
金发仔 这全是我们的
Blondie! It's all ours, Blondie.
你在开玩笑吧
You're joking, Blondie.
你不会和我开这种玩笑吧
You wouldn't play a joke on me like that.
不是玩笑 是绞索 图科
It's no joke. It's a rope, Tuco.
站上去 把头伸进套索里
Now I want you to stand up there and put your head in that noose.
对了 就像以前一样
Well, now, seems just like old times.
四份给你
Four for you
四份…
and four...
给我
Four for me.
金发仔
Hey, Blondie.
图科 抱歉啦
Sorry, Tuco.
金毛小子…
Blondie...
金发仔！
Blondie!
Blondie.
金发仔！
Blondie!
你这个杂种
You son of a bitch
金发仔
Blondie!
小人
坏人
和
好人
嘿 金发仔
Hey, Blondie!
你知道你算什么东西吗？
You know what you are?
纯粹一个下流无耻的杂种！
Just a dirty son of a bitch!